A Guide to the Charles Bos Photograph Collection, 1974-1987
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Charles Bos Photograph Collection 1974-1987
Thomas Balch Library
VC 0024
This collection consists of 113 color slides, taken from 1974 to 1987. Images focus on the Leesburg historic district and include the Aldie Mill.
Charles A. Bos
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Marilyn Bos, Leesburg, VA
Alternative Form Available
Digital surrogates
Accruals
2008.0014
Biographical Information
Charles A. Bos was born on 1 June 1940 in North Tonawanda, New York and grew up in Mentor, Ohio. He attended Oberlin College where he studied German and met his wife, Marilyn Whitney. In 1962, a few months before graduation, the couple married. That same year, they moved to Brentwood, Maryland where Bos took a job as a technical writer for the Naval Ordnance Laboratory. Although he liked writing, he did not enjoy government employment and decided in 1965 to pursue his passion for auto repair as a profession. In 1970, the Bos family moved to Leesburg, Virginia and purchased a circa 1830's home where they raised three daughters: Margot, Karla and Lisa. He also opened the Leesburg Import Service, an automobile repair shop, and managed it for twenty years until he retired.
Bos was civic-minded. His enthusiasm for renovating his historic Loudoun County home eventually led him to join Leesburg's Board of Architectural Review in the 1970's, to serve on the board of the Loudoun Restoration and Preservation Society and to initiate its first newsletter. He was elected to the Leesburg Town Council. Additionally, Bos was appointed to fill a vacancy on the Loudoun County Board of Supervisors and subsequently served a full term. He was one of the founders in 1976 for Leesburg's August Court Days, a community celebration that included music, crafts, food, and re-enactors dressed in period clothes. It was during the August Court Days that Bos's vision of concerts on the Courthouse lawn emerged, which materialized as the annual Bluemont Summer Concert Series.
Bos' diverse interests also included golfing, travel and music. Charles Bos died after a three year struggle with non-Hodgkin's lymphoma at the age of 64 on 25 May 2005.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 113 color slides, taken from 1974 to 1987; the CD contains low resolution copies of 92. Images focus on the Leesburg historic district and include the Aldie Mill. Images are individually catalogued in PastPerfect, Thomas Balch Library's visual collections database available onsite, and may be identified in the online index available at www.leesburgva.gov/ThomasBalchLibrary/SpecialCollections by searching vc_0024.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
"'Chuck' Bos, community leader, dies," Loudoun Times-Mirror, A-22, 1 June 2005.
"Remembering a Man of Vision Leesburg Loses a Leader, Friend," Washington Post www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2005/06/03/AR2005060302096.html, accessed 12 April 2010.
Other Finding Aid
Past Perfect Catalogue records
Technical Requirements
Slide viewer, electronic media
Related Material
None
Contents List
- (1)
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- rooftops], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- Garrett Insurance Agency], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof - Daniel Losh House], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof - North King Street], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof - North King Street], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof - Loudoun County Courthouse Lawn], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof - Loudoun County Courthouse], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof], 1974
  - [Views ofrom Old Hotel Roof], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof - Loudoun County Courthouse], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof - Loudoun County Courthouse], 1974
- (2)
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof], 1974
  - [Views from Old Hotel Roof], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- old water tower], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- old water tower], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- old water tower], 1974
  - [Views of Leesburg From Old Hotel Roof -- old water tower], 1974
  - Loudoun County Courthouse from the balcony of the Leesburg Inn, 1974
  - Loudoun County Courthouse from the balcony of the Leesburg Inn, 1974
  - Residence 26 N. King, 3/4/1976
  - Harris Agency 23 N. King, 3/4/1976
  - Grass Area O'Conner Realty/Customs Rugs, 3/4/1976
  - Right Entrance King Street PN, 3/4/1976
  - Main Entrance PNB, 3/4/1976
  - Jefferson S+L 7 N. King, 3/4/1976
  - New County Building, 3/4/1976
  - Court House Front + Lawn, 3/4/1976
  - Courthouse Corner Lawn, 3/4/1976
  - Court House Rear, 3/4/1976
  - Admin Bldg., 3/4/1976
  - Clerk's Office, 3/4/1976
  - Rear View Between Ad. Bldg + Clerk Office, 3/4/1976
  - Gibson Bldg, 3/4/1976
  - P.O. Parking Lot 15 E. Market St., 3/4/1976
- (3)
  - Harrison Bldg + Law Office, 3/4/1976
  - Barrister Bldg Front Pk. Lot, 3/4/1976
  - Barrister Bldg Front Pk. Lot, 3/4/1976
  - Pk. Lot - T/M P/P NAB, 3/4/1976
  - Pk. Lot P/P + Rear NAB, 3/4/1976
  - Pk. Lot Dentist Bldg, 3/4/1976
  - Pk Alley T/M, 3/4/1976
  - North Ameri. Bank S King, 3/4/1976
  - Raflo Bldg, 3/4/1976
  - Bi-Cent Office, 3/4/1976
  - PNB Drive-In Bldg + Lot, 3/4/1976
  - Leesburg Senior Center, 3/4/1976
  - Walkway Between Leesburg Florist + Laurel Brigade, 3/4/1976
  - Municipal Bldg Lawn, 3/4/1976
  - Tally-Ho Theater, 3/4/1976
  - Municipal Pk Lot Market + Wirt, 3/4/1976
  - Municipal Pk Lot Market from Wirt St, 3/4/1976
  - Municipal Pk Lot Market from W Loudon St, 3/4/1976
  - Municipal Lot, 3/4/1976
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
- (4)
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - [Aldie Mill], 1977-09 ca
  - ACD [Annual Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1978-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1980-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1980-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1980-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1980-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1980-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days] Peter Dunning, 1981-08 ca
- (5)
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1981-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1981-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1981-08 ca
  - ACD [Annual Court Days] John Jackson, 1981-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1982-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days] Ray Baine, 1982-08 ca
  - ACD [August Court Days], 1982-08 ca
  - [Saffer Mill during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station] with Beck Dickerson, 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station] with Beck Dickerson, 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station] with Beck Dickerson, 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - [during construction of Market Station], 1985
  - Dedication Day Ball's Bluff, 1986 ca
  - Concert Series, 1986 ca
  - ACD [Annual Court Days] Old Town Council Bldg, 1987-09 ca
- (AV 003)
  - Charles Bos Collection, Views of Leesburg, 2 June 2008